# Jason Yau

260 King St. #403 San Francisco, CA 94107 (310) 938-4582 • <u>Jason@jkyau.com</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I come from a strong engineering background with a focus on consumer and mobile applications. With experience at top companies including Apple, Beats Music, Samsung, Nokia, and Qualcomm, I am a leader who gets the job done and can architect scalable, service-oriented systems. I know how to build a core team with a clear direction to construct a quality product.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**DWELL** San Francisco, CA *Vice President of Engineering* Jan. 2015 - Nov. 2016

- · Joined Dwell to shift the the company's focus from media to a software company.
- · Built a new online community for dwell.com and iOS app -- launched in August 2016.
- · Led the recruiting and management of the API, Web, iOS, and QA teams.
- · The API, Web, and iOS apps were built in javascript using Node.js, React, and React-Native.
- · Worked closely with product to turn roadmaps into actionable engineering processes.

APPLE San Francisco, CA

Software Engineering Manager

Aug. 2015 - Jan. 2015

- · Joined the iTunes engineering team as part of the Beats Music and Apple merger.
- · Managed the Beats Music Developer Platform and Partner Integrations teams.
- · Responsible for the development of the Beats Music and Apple Music Apple TV application.

**BEATS MUSIC** San Francisco, CA **Principal** Nov. 2013 - Aug. 2015

- · Managed the Beats Music Developer Platform and Partner Integrations teams.
- · Responsible for the SDKs, REST APIs, and Developer Portal -- launched at SXSW 2014.
- · Managed third party hardware and software integrations between Beats Music and partners. · Built meaningful integrations with Sonos, Chevy, Southwest, AT&T, EA, and Microsoft.

# SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS

San Francisco, CA

Director of Engineering

Oct. 2012 - Nov. 2013

- · Managed the API and Android team for Samsung's first idea laboratory.
- · Focused on bridging devices like TVs, mobile phones, and automobiles through software.
- · Developed a REST API framework in node is to support 3rd party development.
- · Built a simple and more streamlined homescreen for Android.
- · Spoke at engineering conferences on behalf of the Open Innovation Center.

#### THISMOMENT INC.

San Francisco, CA

Sept. 2010 – Oct. 2012

- Director of Engineering
- · Responsible for developing the SDKs, REST APIs, and Developer Portal.

· Managed the Developer Platform and Partner Integrations teams.

- · Worked closely with partners to build meaningful integrations with the platform.

NOKIA R&D Aug. 2009 – Sept. 2010

Sr. Software Engineer, Nokia Web Run Time

72ANDSUNNY Jan. 2009 – Aug. 2009

 $Head\ of\ Creative\ Technology$ 

YAHOO! BRICKHOUSE R&D Aug. 2007 – Jan. 2009

Sr. Software Engineer

QUALCOMM July 2003 – Aug. 2007

Software Engineer

# **EDUCATION**

2002 - 2006

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA SAN DIEGO

Computer Science and Engineering / Management Science

 $\cdot$  Extra Curricular: UCSD Snowboarding Team

# **ACTIVITIES**

- · Red Cross Lifeguard
- · Surfing, Golfing, Fly Fishing, Design

# **SKILLS & EXPERTISE**

SOA, React, React-Native, Node.js, AWS, Mongo, Javascript, Swift, Objective-C, Java